Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Main engine output rising.
Good. It's stabilized.
The Yamato has arrived.
Strange…
What gives them such motivation ?
There's no end.
Front guards, focus on the "Needles" coming from ahead.
Rear guards, aim at the enemy above.
Roger !
It is fate.
The power of fate connects the ship and us.
Those ghosts don't know their place.
Telezart defense fleet annihilation confirmed.
Vital signs of both of the Goland bodies are lost.
Gather all divisions !
Annihilate them along with the
advanced unit that landed earlier !
I'll go, too.
Indeed, life is unpredictable.
Until my time comes, I'll hold onto
the hope of survival to fulfill my life.
Hear that, Yamato ?
Second landing team, move out !
Space Cavalry, prepare to
receive special equipment.
Roger.
Can't we just destroy the
rock bed with the Yamato ?
The main guns are inadequate, and the
wave motion gun would destroy Telezart.
We must depend on the wave motion
excavator the First Officer developed.
Believe in Kodai and the others.
Akira…
Don't talk.
You'll survive.
That person says you're safe.
That person…?
Enemy unit approaching from 9 o'clock.
It's the Medarusa class modified tanks.
Ensign Yamamoto, we'll hold our ground,
so secure the safety of yourself and the injured.
Roger.
Spread out, engage at will.
Is it unmanned ?
Take this !
These are unmanned.
Aim for the control system on the bridge.
Got it !
Die, die, die, die already !
Did we manage to hold out ?
Deputy Commander, a number of enemy
reinforcement units detected 10 kilometers away.
What ?
That many ?
What're you going to do, Deputy Commander ?
Isn't it obvious ?
Don't let them come any closer.
Roger that.
We can't let the Yamato crew die.
We can finally pay off our debt.
Exactly.
We were supposed to die back there.
Hold on !
Nagakura, sorry for making you wait.
Commander.
Everyone, leave the area immediately !
Take this !
Commander.
Those small "Needles" will come.
watch yourselves.
Roger.
Not bad.
But when humans act like that,
there's always something else going on.
Fire the Helvestia Cannon.
They know about us ?
Damn, why can't it be more accurate ?
Half of the relays were lost because of the Yamato's wave motion gun. The current accuracy is our best.
It's only a copy after all ?
Dammit !
Reflective Satellite Cannon ?!
How ?
They stole Garmillas technology ?
They captured Garmillas scientists to develop weapons.
Lieutenant Keyman, if that's the case, the basic controls must be derived from Garmillas ones.
We don't have time to
destroy each and every satellite.
Just destroy the relay control satellite.
If we trace this control signal,
we can find the target's location, right ?
Cover me.
Got it.
Pull back !
All units, retreat to the rendezvous point !
It's dangerous !
Please evacuate !
Almost.
Is that it ?
An identical copy.
Those who steal someone else's property...
...deserve to be punished.
What the hell…?!
Destroyed ?
300 seconds till explosion.
Good !
Let's get out of here !
All personnel, head to the
rendezvous point at once.
Guys, you heard that.
The rock bed will explode soon.
The surface…
Commander !
Here comes the big boss, huh ?
Everyone, get down !
Is everyone okay ?
We've lost Ohmiya and Yahata's vitals.
Anyone with functional weapons ?
All units' output is down to 20% because of the
interference wave of the wave motion resonance.
Got it.
All units, withdraw immediately.
Get out before the second shot.
Roger.
Nagakura…
Yes, Commander ?
Go on ahead. I'll catch up.
Six…
…five…
…four…
…three…
…two…
…one…
Shockwave is spreading throughout the planet.
The sealing rock beds are
breaking up due to a chain reaction.
Zantz Zarvival.
That's my inherited name.
And you ?
Saito Hajime, a space cavalryman.
You killed my men.
Self destruct ?
Like hell !
What the hell ?! Friggin' idiot.
Course clear.
We can descend to Terezalium.
The source of Teresa's message.
Use caution, Kodai.
Aye, sir.
Without the sun, how…
That must act like the sun, I bet.
That's…
Is Teresa inside it ?
What was Gatlantis trying to do here ?
Hey, look.
What's going on ?
Teresa. That's Teresa.
I am Teresa.
Teresa of Telezart.
Teresa, we received your message,
and came all the way here.
Why us ?
You could have sent your
message to anyone in the universe.
I didn't make the choice.
The Yamato was destined to come here.
Destined ?
What do you mean ?
Teresa, you're a higher dimensional life-form who resides in the upper dimension, aren't you ?
Higher dimensional life-form ?
We have to come to this place in
order to hear your real voice, correct ?
Yes. You can hear my voice only
when you're in my dimension.
The Terezalium is a gate for that purpose.
The people of Telezart gave up on their
bodies and crossed the gate to heaven alive.
Teresa, you're their collective mind.
You reside between this world and the afterworld,
watching the universe from its beginning to the end.
She lives in the world
where time can be visualized.
We're standing at the entrance.
Entrance ?
Are we at the entrance to Heaven ?
Then what's destined to happen to the Yamato ?
You know of the White Comet, don't you ?
Yes, we regard it as the Gatlantian home planet.
It is a relic of the ancient Archelians from long ago.
As they planted the seeds of human life throughout space, they prepared safeguards, as well.
If the seeded lives develop in the wrong direction,
a device would destroy each and every one of them.
Then Gatlantis is…
All living things have one purpose.
It's to survive.
But Gatlantis is different.
They revived the ark of destruction.
Their advancement will not stop until they've annihilated all human life in the universe.
You must confront the White Comet Empire…
…not only for Earth, but also
for all living things in space.
And you already know the outcome, don't you ?
Saito, don't.
If I tell you about the future, it will change.
That would be overstepping my bounds.
What's that ?
Those who have abandoned physical bodies
shouldn't intervene in the world of physical entities.
All I'm allowed to do is pray.
A god-like civilization has left a destructive device…
We don't know if we can defeat
them even with the entire Earth force.
Any hints ?
Can we have any hints for the battle ?
You came here, which means
you and I are bound by fate.
"Yamato" means great harmony.
Great harmony…
Harmony is a field created by
the lives brought together by fate.
Fate is a power that connects dissimilar entities.
Like how gravity works, fate connects events by acting across the wall of dimensions.
The power of fate exceeds any laws of physics.
It can't be overturned no matter
how powerful the protection may be.
Great harmony…
The Yamato is at the center of fate,
and it will stop the ark of doom.
Teresa…
Fate grows…painfully at times.
With him as well.
It's been a while, gentlemen of the Yamato.
Episode 14
Zarvival's Onslaught and the Discovery of Teresa
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Saijo Miki:
Kato Saburo:
Yamamoto Akira:
Tsurumi Jiro:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Mugihito
Moriya Satomi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Tanaka Rie
Komoto Keisuke
Togire yuku manazashi wa...
Your fading gaze turns to...
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Kurata Masaru:
Hijikata Ryu:
Desler:
Keyman:
Zorder:
Teresa:
Zarvival:
Space Cavalryman A:
Space Cavalryman B:
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Kiyohito Yoshikai
Ishizuka Unsho
Yamadera Koichi
Kamioya Hiroshi
Tezuka Hideaki
Kanda Sayaka
Yara Yusaku
Fujinuma Kento
Yano Masaaki
...Yuuja no tashika na rashinban
...a trusted compass of a warrior
Yakusoku wa nai mama ni...
Without any promise...
...Yatsura mo ikari wo agedasu
...they will weigh anchor in response
Kowarekaketa kono sekai wa...
The half-destroyed world has named...
...Te wo sashinoberu hito no na wo
...the people who can lend a hand
Namari iro no kotae ga...
A lead-colored response...
...Kurayami ni tsumetaku tsukihanasu
...cut coldly through the darkness
Inochi wo tsumuide tokoshie no tami
Spin the thread of life for the everlasting journey
Kibou no kuni e
To the nation of hope
Otoko no sadame ni seigi tsuranuki
Stay faithful to justice in men's destiny
Torawareta ashita wo sukuu no sa
Save the besieged future
Shuuen ni mukaeba itsuka rifujin na sekai ga...
When the end comes near, the unexpected world will...
...Kurenai no sakazuki de otagai no yuuki tataeyou
...cheer both sides with a crimson cup
Hakai to souzou densetsu no kake...
Destruction and creation, and legendary wagers...
...Yatsura mo onaji sa
...fall onto both sides
Tatakai no hibuta
The outbreak of war
Towa ni kirarete honou no okite
It repeats endlessly in a destined blaze
Kodoku to shouri ga korogariochiru...
Loneliness and victory will eventually be known...
...Mekuru meku uchuu no hate made
...throughout dazzling space
Preview
Why don't we call an end to this, Fuhrer Desler ?
How can we end things that haven't
even been started yet, Yamato lad ?
Episode 15
Teresa, Cry For Desler !